<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Lawrence Lim</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lawrence Lim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Website Workshop</title>
      <link>/article/personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/personal-website/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started Install Code Editor: VScode
Install Package Manager: Homebrew
/bin/bash -c &amp;#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)&amp;#34; Install Static Site Generator Hugo
brew install hugo Follow the directions on the terminal output Optional: Install Github GLI (if you want to deploy your website)
brew install gh Once installed, run gh auth login and follow the directions on the terminal Create your Website Create Hugo Project
hugo new site quickstart -f yml Install Theme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethereum Crowd Funding – Full Stack Solidity &amp; JavaScript DApp</title>
      <link>/project/hh-fund-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 01:26:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hh-fund-me/</guid>
      <description>About The Project My Ethereum Crowd Funding project is full stack decentralized application built who&amp;rsquo;s backend (GH repo) is built with Solidity and the Hardhat Ethereum development framework. Tests are done with Mocha &amp;amp; Chai in Javascript. Additionally, it utilizes Chainlink pricefeed oracles and its frontend (GH repo) is coded in vanilla HTML/CSS and Javascript. This project was created as a part of Patrick Collin&amp;rsquo;s Solidity and Javascript smart contract course with Free Code Camp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Contract Raffle – DApp Backend</title>
      <link>/project/hh-raffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 01:26:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hh-raffle/</guid>
      <description>About The Project My Smart Conract Raffle project is the Solidity smart contract backend of automated and decentralized raffle. The DApp utilizes verifiable random numbers from Chainlink VRFs and uses Chainlink keepers to update or &amp;ldquo;upkeep&amp;rdquo; the live contract to maintain the integrity of the raffle. This project was created as a part of Patrick Collin&amp;rsquo;s Solidity and Javascript smart contract course with Free Code Camp.
Getting Started Prerequisites yarn Installation Clone the repo (backend) git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MeChat - Python GUI Desktop Chat App</title>
      <link>/project/mechat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mechat/</guid>
      <description>About The Project Presentation Slides
MeChat (GH Repo) Up is a Python GUI desktop chat app built with Tkinter. This app was also created as the final project for NYU Shanghai&amp;rsquo;s Introduction to Computer Science course. Here we will detail several of its key features and outline its development lifecycle.
Built With Our chat application used the following languages and libraries in our development.
Python Tkinter GUI Library Ngrok Network Application Getting Started Prerequisites This project depends on the python tkinter GUI library and ngrok network app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BTC Data Analysis Project - Which is the Most Hyped Crypto?</title>
      <link>/project/btc-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/btc-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Project Information Our research question for our project is: What is the most hyped cryptocurrency and is it Bitcion? We used many data sources for our research, including Bitcoin block data, cryptocurrency price data (from Yahoo Finance), and Google Trends search data. Additionally, we utilized data analysis techniques such as correlation, regression plotting, min-max scaling, and more.
Recorded Video Presentation of our research: Google Slides Presentation: Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitalik&#39;s Vision - EthCC Paris Recap</title>
      <link>/article/vitalik-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/vitalik-vision/</guid>
      <description>Vitalik Buterin recently spoke at EthParis 2022, outlining his long-term and short-term goals for Ethereum. We examine the roadmap he lays out and will also break down vital technical features to play an essential role in Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s future.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim original article linked here
Prerequisites Knowledge of Proof of Work (PoW), Proof of Stake (PoS), and [Layer-2 (L2)](https://ethereum.org/en/layer-2/#:~:text=A layer 2 is a separate blockchain that extends Ethereum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zkSync vs StarkWare - What&#39;s the difference between the top two ZK Rollups?</title>
      <link>/article/zksync-vs-starkware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/zksync-vs-starkware/</guid>
      <description>We compare zkSync and StarkNet - two prominent ZK-rollups scaling the Ethereum network. What are ZK-Rollups? How are zkSync and StarkNet different? What are SNARKs and STARKs? We answer these questions and more while also exploring each protocol&amp;rsquo;s respective roadmaps and ecosystems.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim. Original article linked here
Table of Contents Prerequisites Background Zero-Knowledge Rollups Optimistic vs. ZK Rollups zkSync vs. StarkNet SNARKs vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimism vs. Arbitrum - A Complete Comparison</title>
      <link>/article/optimism-vs-arbitrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/optimism-vs-arbitrum/</guid>
      <description>Optimism and Arbitrum , two of the largest layer-two (L2) solutions that utilize Optimistic rollup technology to scale the Ethereum network. I will do a full comparison in this article.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim. Original article linked here
Background Optimism and Arbitrum are two of the largest layer-two (L2) solutions that utilize Optimistic rollup technology to scale the Ethereum network.
Source: https://l2fees.info/
At present, Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s high transaction fees and limited throughput of ~15 transactions per second (TPS) severely limits its scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital RMB: Revolutionary Technology or Not?</title>
      <link>/article/digital-rmb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/digital-rmb/</guid>
      <description>After the pilot of e-CNY was rolled out in 10 cities across China in August of 2021, news outlets all over the world swarmed to cover the new burgeoning technology[8]. After the initial buzz of the pilot died down, one question many people in China and the international media had on their minds was whether e-CNY was truly going to be the disruptive revolutionary technology that the People’s Bank of China (PBOC) wants it to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? Hi, I’m Lawrence Lim and I’m currently a Sophomore CS student based in Shanghai. I have experience researching web3 protocols and currently focus my personal projects on smart contract development. Besides programming, i&amp;rsquo;m often playing soccer, going to the gym, or organizing community events in Shanghai.
I’m also very passionate about open source and am always interested in hearing about opportunities in tech especially in web3. Never hesitate to reach out or connect!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email ll4715@nyu.edu Social Media: LinkedIn Github Twitter Telegram </description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
