<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Lawrence Lim</title>
    <link>/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Lawrence Lim</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vitalik&#39;s Vision - EthCC Paris Recap</title>
      <link>/article/vitalik-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/vitalik-vision/</guid>
      <description>Vitalik Buterin recently spoke at EthParis 2022, outlining his long-term and short-term goals for Ethereum. We examine the roadmap he lays out and will also break down vital technical features to play an essential role in Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s future.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim original article linked here
Prerequisites Knowledge of Proof of Work (PoW), Proof of Stake (PoS), and [Layer-2 (L2)](https://ethereum.org/en/layer-2/#:~:text=A layer 2 is a separate blockchain that extends Ethereum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>zkSync vs StarkWare - What&#39;s the difference between the top two ZK Rollups?</title>
      <link>/article/zksync-vs-starkware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/zksync-vs-starkware/</guid>
      <description>We compare zkSync and StarkNet - two prominent ZK-rollups scaling the Ethereum network. What are ZK-Rollups? How are zkSync and StarkNet different? What are SNARKs and STARKs? We answer these questions and more while also exploring each protocol&amp;rsquo;s respective roadmaps and ecosystems.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim. Original article linked here
Table of Contents Prerequisites Background Zero-Knowledge Rollups Optimistic vs. ZK Rollups zkSync vs. StarkNet SNARKs vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimism vs. Arbitrum - A Complete Comparison</title>
      <link>/article/optimism-vs-arbitrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/article/optimism-vs-arbitrum/</guid>
      <description>Optimism and Arbitrum , two of the largest layer-two (L2) solutions that utilize Optimistic rollup technology to scale the Ethereum network. I will do a full comparison in this article.
This article was first published to TokenInsight by Lawrence Lim. Original article linked here
Background Optimism and Arbitrum are two of the largest layer-two (L2) solutions that utilize Optimistic rollup technology to scale the Ethereum network.
Source: https://l2fees.info/
At present, Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s high transaction fees and limited throughput of ~15 transactions per second (TPS) severely limits its scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
